asa.org.uk 2012-05-06

# Privacy policy - Advertising Standards Authority

## Terms and Conditions

## How we use your data and how we use cookies

### About ASA

This is the Privacy Policy of the Advertising Standards Authority Limited (ASA), Mid City Place, 71 High Holborn, London WC1V 6QT.

The ASA takes its responsibilities on the confidentiality of your personal information very seriously. To comply with the Data Protection Act, processing by the Advertising Standards Authority (ASA), the Advertising Standards Authority (Broadcast) Ltd (ASA(B)), the Committee of Advertising Practice (CAP) and the Broadcast Committee of Advertising Practice (BCAP) Ltd is covered by notifications with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

Our Privacy Policy is set out below. Please read this Policy with care; it describes how we will process your data. If you have any questions or comments, e-mail [data.protection@asa.org.uk](mailto:data.protection@asa.org.uk).

### Where your data is held

Your personal data is held on secure servers operated by ASA, ASA(B), CAP and BCAP and agencies contracted by us. We do not transfer your data outside the EEA and we comply with the protection offered to you under the Data Protection Act 1998.

### Data Security

Personal data is collected and stored securely subject to stringent security measures and is protected against misuse. When we use external data processing services, we do so only under strict contractual terms to mirror the security policies that we have in place.

### The information we collect

As well as name and contact details, we ask you to supply information about the type of organisation you work for or to tell us if you are a consumer; that and any other information we gather about you will help us tailor the information we send you to your needs. 

### What we do with your data and what we don’t do

We shall process the data you supply to give you information and advice about your complaint. If you have given your consent, we may communicate with you via e-mail, SMS, post or telephone about the activities of the ASA, ASA(B), CAP and BCAP.  We will not share your data for marketing purposes outside the ASA, ASA (Broadcast), CAP and BCAP.

This website explains how to subscribe to ASA and CAP communications. If you want to update your personal data and preferences for communications from us please go to login and go to My Account. 

### External links

The ASA website contains links to websites operated by third parties under different privacy policies.   Should you choose one of those links, you will be leaving the ASA site and this Privacy Policy will no longer apply.

### Access to your information

You have the right to ask ASA for a copy of the personal information ASA, ASA(B), CAP and BCAP hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) and to correct any inaccuracies in that information. If you would like access to your information, please contact [dataprotection@asa.org.uk](mailto:dataprotection@asa.org.uk). 

### Cookie Policy

The ASA website cookie policy has been developed in conjunction with the Interactive Advertising Bureau Cookie initiative ([www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)) to tell users what cookies are used on this site and how to manage them.

#### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a text-only string that is entered into the cookie file or "memory" of the browser on your computer by website owners and content providers. It will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. Two types of cookies are used on this website – session cookies which are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser until you close your browser, and persistent cookies which remain in the cookie file of your browser for much longer (though how long will depend on the "lifetime" of the specific cookie). For more information about cookies please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

#### Cookies used on this website

Permanent cookies (with an expiry time of 1 hr): This means that,

  * If you login and check the remember me, browse through the website and then close the browser, you will not be required to log in as long as you are within that hour time frame. If you come back to the website after 3 hrs, you will be required to log in since the cookie has gone past its expiry time. 
  * If you login and check the remember me, browse through the website and then hit the sign out button, your cookie will be automatically removed since you’ve explicitly signed out. You will still be required to log in next time you visit the site. 

Personal data may be processed in conjunction with these cookies in order to achieve these purposes. For more information about how we process personal data, please see the details above in our privacy policy. 

Because of the dynamic and interactive nature of our website, services or content may from time to time, be provided by parties with whom we do not have a direct relationship. In providing those services or content, those parties may also be setting and using cookies. Because we do not have a direct relationship with those parties, we cannot ensure that this policy covers their use of their cookies. However, you can check on any page, at any time, who is using cookies by using the most current versions of browser technology, which provides you with the ability to choose which cookies to accept or reject. For a further explanation of this, please visit the "Introduction to P3P" of [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

#### How to manage the use of cookies at our website

All browser technologies enable you to manage the cookies in the cookie folder of your browser. This means that you can either delete cookies from your cookie folder once you have finished your visit at our site or you can set your preferences with regard to the use of cookies before you begin surfing our website. Please note that deleting or rejecting cookies may affect your user experience of our website. For more information on deleting and rejecting cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Copyright

Copyright in all information, text and images featured on our site is owned by or licensed to ASA, ASA(B), CAP or BCAP. Provided that you acknowledge ASA as the source of the information, you are entitled to download one copy of any of the works on this site for the purposes of study or journalism but you are not entitled to make more copies of that work.

### Changes to this policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we shall post changes on this page so that you are always aware of how ASA uses your personal information.

* * *

The Advertising Standards Authority Ltd  
Mid City Place  
71 High Holborn  
London  
WC1V 6QT
